Pavel Buramensky

Senior Front-end Developer

Kazakhstan, Astana paulbu.com mail@paulbu.com +7 705-201-23-77

Summary

- 10+ years of front-end focused experience
- Combine strong programming skills with good handle on UX design
- Wild about creating an immersive and sleek user experience
- Master Degree in Computer Science
- Open to relocation and remote work

Objective

I have been doing front-end development for over a decade, mostly for complex web applications, like multitrack audio workstation or electronic health record system. Besides, I really enjoy creating stylish web-sites, fancy CSS/SVG animations and data visualization. No matter what I do, my ultimate goal is to deliver a first-class user experience.

A combination of expertise in Front-end development and User experience helps me to achieve this goal and develop complex apps from concept to production, find an optimal balance between aesthetics, efforts and performance, effectively communicate with product owners, design and backend dev teams.

Professional skills

What I can do:

- develop and maintain complex web apps with modern JS frameworks (preferably Vue, but I have worked with React and AngularJS too)
- create reasonably pixel-perfect, adaptive, rich-media web interfaces with a nontrivial design
- make wireframes and user flows based on business requirements, create interactive HTML prototypes
- manage a small team of developers in Agile process. However, I prefer coding and UX design more

Programming/Markup languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, LESS, JSS

JavaScript Frameworks and SSR

Vue (with Vuex, Vue Router, Vuetify and Vuelidate), React, AngularJS 1.x, NuxtJS, Gatsby

Browser APIs

Web Audio (Web Audio API, MIDI API), Web Graphics (SVG, Canvas), Data Storage (Local Storage, IndexedDB), Web Worker

UX/UI design tools

Photoshop, Figma, Illustrator, Balsamig

Infrastructure

Git (GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket), Bundling/Automation (Webpack, gulp), Docker

Server communication

REST API, GraphQL, WebSocket

Code quality and performance

Linting, Formatting, Style guides, Unit-testing (Jest, Vue Test Utils, Mocha/Ava), Documentation (JSDoc, Swagger), Code review, Web page performance

Workflow & Methodology

Agile SCRUM/KANBAN, JIRA, Confluence, Trello

Languages

Russian (Native), English (B2), German(A1)

Work experience

Lead Front-end developer / Holmusk / July 2018 - May 2021

Holmusk is a data science and health technology company that aims to reverse chronic disease and behavioral health issues.

Used skills

VueJS (with Vuex and Vue Router), Vuetify, TypeScript, Jest, Vue Test Utils, FHIR API, HTML5/CSS3, SASS, UX expertise, Team leading, SCRUM

Responsibilities

- Delivered a complex front-end application (electronic health record system) with Vue and RESTful FHIR API
- Communicated with product managers and coordinated with BA, QA and back-end developers to deliver the quality product
- Analyzed the product design complexity, planned the workload, communicated the risks; ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Performed unit, integration, and performance testing
- Led the team, established and maintained code quality standards
- Fine-tuned middle-fidelity wireframes, creating interfaces based on wireframes and UI library
- Documented code and design of the product

Challenges

Working with FHIR API requires a deep dive into the extremely sophisticated domain of Healthcare data management. However, that was worth it because FHIR is a great architectural example of a good organization of complex real data structures.

Also, it was a considerable experience of fully remote work with a team distributed in six different time zones from West Coast (UTC-8) to Singapore (UTC+8).

Lead UI/Front-end developer / Codenetix / Nov. 2016 - July 2018

CODENETIX is a software agency with the focus on complex custom solutions and just a dream team of passionate skillful specialists

Used Skills

ES6, React (with React Router, Redux, SAGA), Gatsby, HTML5/SCSS, CSS and Canvas animation, Docker, UX/UI expertise, Agile

Responsibilities

- Developed and managed robust codebases with appealing interfaces for a variety of applications,
 from design to production
- Made interactive multimedia content and complex animations with Canvas and HTML/CSS
- Defined overall technology direction for the company projects
- Led and mentored the team, established and maintained high code quality standards and best practices
- Assisted in the collection and documentation of user's requirements, development of user stories, estimates and work plans
- Created wireframes and prototypes, occasionally took up UX/UI-design tasks

Challenges

This position gave me a lot of new professional experience. I joined the team at an early stage of its formation and took an active part in its growth and development, forming a great front-end team from scratch.

It was an exceptional experience performing many roles and quickly switching between them and tasks, often outside the front-end of development.

Front-end developer / Bandlab / Sept. 2014 - Oct. 2016

BandLab is a Singapore based social music creation platform, the combination of social network, multitrack audio workstation and VCS-like music storage

Used Skills

Vanilla JS ES5/ES6, AngularJS 1.x, Web Audio API, HTML5, SASS, Canvas, SVG, WebWorkers, IndexedDB, Local Storage, WebRTC, Agile

Responsibilities

 Developed a browser-based multitrack digital audio workstation with AngularJS 1.x. and Web Audio API

Challenges

Making SPA with functionality of GarageBand was an ambiguous challenge that required strong JavaScript skills, profound knowledge of digital signal processing and Web Audio API.

I faced many nontrivial tasks on the way such as multitrack sound mixing, adding audio effects, audio latency detection, sound pitch detection with the use of Fourier analysis and autocorrelation, and so on. The solution of these issues required good math skills, rational usage of design patterns and understanding of sound nature.

Eventually, I am proud of having taken part in creating one of the best web-based audio workstations of today.

Front-end developer /DXC Luxoft /July 2012 - Sept. 2014

Luxoft is a DXC Technology Company, is a digital strategy and software engineering firm, with about 13k employees within its 41 offices in 22 countries.

Used Skills

HTML5, CSS3, LESS, VanillaJS, jQuery, XSLT with .NET-driven CMS (Sitecore, Sharepoint), UI/UX expertise, Agile

Responsibilities

- Created adaptive HTML5/CSS3 layouts with jQuery for projects such as PromSvyazBank public site,
 LikePR OneClick Yakutsk platform, M-Video internal services
- Assisted in the collection and documentation of user's requirements, development of user stories, estimates and work plans
- Optimized front-end for high load sites and mobile devices
- Managed a small team of front-end developers

Challenges

Crafting top notch interfaces for large companies, developing interactive maps, complex client-side data validation and calculations (loan calculators, credit wizards, etc.)

Web developer / Mir IT / June 2011 - July 2012

Mir IT is a small software company focused on web development, design and SEO services

Used Skills

PHP, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, C#, ADO.NET, MS SQL Server, MySQL

Responsibilities

- Developed and tested web sites with LAMP stack and HTML/CSS/jQuery
- Developed electronic document management systems with C# and MS SQL/SQLite

Teaching Assistant / Omsk State Technical University / Sept. 2009 - Sept. 2014

Used Skills

Public speech, explanation and communication skills, research.

Responsibilities

- Developed and conducted courses (Artificial Intelligence Systems, Decision Support System)
- Set up and conducted practical classes (Control theory)
- Conducted exams and assessed students` knowledge

Software developer, 3D artist, Photographer / Freelance / 2008 - 2011

Used Skills

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, C#/ASP.NET, MySQL, 3Ds Max, Sony Vegas, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom

Responsibilities

- Web design and programming with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES5, PHP, C#/ASP.NET, MySQL
- 3d-modelling and animation, video editing
- Event and studio photography

Education

Doctor of Philosophy (postgraduate student), Computer science (unfinished) Omsk State Technical University, 2013 - 2015.

Master of Science, Computer science

Omsk State Technical University, 2009-2011 - GPA 4.9/5.0

Bachelor of Science, Computer science

Omsk State Technical University, 2005-2009 - GPA 4.6/5.0